Lacourdaire (Lucky) Camargo

Luckycamargo1011@gmail.com • 773-766-0176 • www.linkedin.com/in/lacourdaire-lucky-camargo/

Career Profile

Interdisciplinary analytical and data-driven professional with over 10 years of experience in education and public health programs focused on addressing systemic issues related to social determinants of health, policy, and 5+ years of experience in program administration and management.

Education

University of Illinois at Chicago – College of Urban Planning and Public Affairs Master of Science, Civic Analytics Expected 2024

Northeastern Illinois University in Chicago

Bachelor of Arts in Economics, minor in Philosophy

Skills and Competencies

- Data Analysis Software: GIS, R
 and GitHub,
- Bicultural/Bilingual Spanish-Speaker
- Survey Design and Implementation
- Systems and Policy Analysis
 Qualitative and Quantitative Research and Analysis Methods
- Supervision Experience

2020

- Program Planning and Evaluation
- Community/Stakeholder Engagement

August 2021–June 2022

Professional Experience

Intern June 2022-Present

Office of Fiscal and Economic Research Illinois Department of Revenue, *Chicago, IL*

- Research and bill analysis on diverse set of economic proposals associated with taxes administered and industries: Income Inequality; Individual Income tax; Sales and use tax.
- Assist with the calculation of revenue impact for legislative bill proposals by collecting data and synthesizing figures.

Community Engagement Specialist

Sinai Urban Health Institute (SUHI)

Sinai Health Systems, Chicago, IL

- Developed and maintained relationships with community organizations, healthcare providers, and other stakeholders to increase awareness of SUHI activities and engage them in research initiatives.
- Manage and oversee evaluation dissemination activities by assigning tasks, managing schedules, reviewing work, and providing feedback.
- Presented research findings to internal and external audiences.
- Implemented the community engagement evaluation plan through utilization of a variety of tools (focus groups, stakeholder surveys, participant surveys, and admissions data).
- Analyzed evaluation data through the usage of qualitative and quantitative methodology.
- Organize, administer, coordinate, and follow up on focus group research associated with the evaluation of public health programs on south and west side Chicago communities with staff and patients.
- Present, lead and facilitate all aspects of SUHI's Community Advisory Committee meetings, including member relationship development and management, ongoing member engagement, meeting planning and facilitation, onboarding and orientation, and communication.
- Oversee the timely disbursement of payments to Community Advisory Committee members.
- Synthesize evaluation findings in full evaluation reports and develop accompanying data visualization, such as infographics.

1

- Establish linkages and partnerships with healthcare providers and service agencies to facilitate resource sharing, gather information and facilitate technical assistance.
- Provide logistical and research support to the strategy evaluation team.
- Develop and maintain research notes related to the evaluation of grant program meetings.
- Prepare monthly presentations for Community Advisory Committee that adheres to research aims of grant program.
- Initiate and establish external partnerships to collect data for research opportunities.
- Contribute and assist in writing findings for research reports for funders on grants.
- Develop data collection and analysis tools to support program evaluation.
- Conduct focus group interviews and synthesize analysis.
- Assist with the preparation of narrative reports on program activities for Mid-year and End of year reports for funders.
- Conduct, lead coordination and scheduling of survey collection for Equity First Vaccine Initiative, a Nationwide survey funded by Rockefeller Foundation.
- Interface with community-based organizations and sector specific contacts externally to expand and foster new relationships and engagement pathways toward public health collaborations

Research Assistant January 2020 – July 2021

Northeastern Illinois University, Economics Department, Chicago, IL

- Identify, collect, and analyze land values for select Cook County, Illinois townships for years 1946- 1960
 utilizing Olcott Value Book Archives relating to research that evaluates redlining policies, land values and
 spatial location.
- Utilizing QGIS, create map that digitizes and merges non-spatial data to spatial shapefiles.
- Retrieve annexation plat records for select Cook County suburbs through the Cook County Recorder of Deeds archives to review and identify race restriction covenants recorded on plat of subdivision.

Research Assistant June 2020 – July 2020

University of Illinois, MBA 594, Management of Public Health Course, Chicago, IL

- Collect digital research related to public health management policy, theory and practice for China, USA,
 Cuba, and England
- File and track FOIA requests with CDPH and IDPH that provide distribution of covid testing access, frequency, and demographic breakdown by COVID-19 testing site in City of Chicago.
- Collect and organize written research from publications on COVID-19 activities by local & state public health departments, evaluating cutbacks and privatization activity since January 1, 2020.
- Coordinated and presented demographic/spatial data relating to COVID-19 testing access by Chicago zip code

Box Office and Stage Manager

March 2018 – May 2020

Northeastern Illinois University, Chicago, IL

- Create and communicate weekly cast rehearsals, call times, performance schedule, and show content: recording specifics on roles and cues for main stage performers.
- Implement and track minor adjustments to sets and equipment.
- Oversee ticket sales and transactions: ensuring the security of money exchanged.

Math Peer Leader July 2019 – August 2019

Northeastern Illinois University, Chicago, IL

- Provide mathematical support to first-time incoming freshmen.
- Work closely with their assigned students throughout each component of the 3-week math session.
- Provide broad academic support and guidance to corresponding campus resources.

Campaign Director

February 2018-February 2019

Aldermanic Election candidate, Richard Juarez, Chicago, IL

- Planned, designed, and managed events such as volunteer training to increase candidate awareness as well as fundraising events.
- Coordinated and scheduled media interviews for the candidate
- Prepared, analyzed, and monitored campaign expenses and revenues.
- Coordinated and implemented door to door canvassing.
- Provide administrative support, including electronic correspondence and filings for campaign disclosures

Mission Advancement and Development Director

November 2015-August 2016

UNO Charter School Network, Chicago, IL

- Developed, executed, and tracked results for annual fundraising plan by securing financial support from individuals, foundations, and corporations.
- Developed proposals and reports for foundation and corporate fundraising

Outreach and Leadership Development Coordinator

January 2014-November 2015

UNO Charter School Network, Chicago, IL

- Development of parent survey that gauge's perceptions and interests around parent engagement and activities
- Planned and administered outreach programs focused on parental engagement reaching 1000+ families.
- · Advanced policy initiatives through local authorizers and the Illinois legislature for school funding equity
- Developed and facilitated graduate support programs for middle school to high school matriculation.
- Interviewed, recruited, trained, and developed staff members/volunteers for community outreach activities and intergovernmental meetings with local and state legislators and stakeholders.
- Design and developed and implemented parent survey that gauge perceptions and interests around parent engagement and activities.
- Planned and administered outreach programs focused on parental engagement reaching 1000+ families.
- Advanced policy initiatives through local authorizers and the Illinois legislature for school funding equity
- Developed and facilitated graduate support programs for middle school to high school matriculation.
- Interviewed, recruited, trained, and developed staff members/volunteers for community outreach activities and intergovernmental meetings with local and state legislators and stakeholders.

Director of UNO 5K Race of the Dead

April 2011-December 2013

UNO Charter School Network, Chicago, IL

- Created a mechanism to incorporate school staff and parent community expertise into the planning and coordination of a the 5k race event in Pilsen.
- survey from the collaborative and presented findings to both community and academic partners Managed a \$130,000 budget including the negotiation of 5k race related service agreements and contracts related to 5k race event purchases.
- Developed and forecasted expense projections with senior and mid-level managers for 5k race event serving 2000+ participant event.
- Developed media plan, established media relations and donor cultivation that exceeded fundraising benchmark by 36%.
- Ensure compliance with insurance, legal, health and safety obligations at events.

Student Experience	
Alpha Chi National Honor Society	2019
Omicron Delta Epsilon (ODE)	2019
Presented Research	
Trading Coal for Diesel: An Analysis on Ambient Air and its Link to Cancer	May 2020
12th Annual Research Symposium, Student Center for Science Engagement, Northeastern Illinois University-Chicago	· }
IL	
Community Involvement and Leadership	
• Lucha Por la Villita, f/k/a Mi Villita Neighbors, Co-Founder, Chicago, IL	2018-Present
• Flu Shot and COVID-19 Vaccine / Testing pop ups, co-lead and coordinate	2020-2023
vaccination events that have served an estimated 3,000 Chicago residents cumulatively,	

2012 - 2020

Lucha Por la Villita, neighborhood collective, Chicago, IL

Chicago Youth Boxing Club, Board of Directors, Vice-Chair, Chicago, IL